oncourselearning.com 2017-01-30

# Privacy Policy | OnCourse Learning

  * [Products & Services](https://www.oncourselearning.com/learning-platform) [

#### Learning Platform

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/learning-platform) [

#### Catalogs

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/catalogs)
  * [About Us](https://www.oncourselearning.com/aboutus) [

#### Company Overview

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/aboutus) [

#### Leadership

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/leadership) [

#### Careers

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/careers) [

#### Partners

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/partners) [

#### Press Releases

](https://www.oncourselearning.com/press-releases)
  * Search

menu

###### This policy was last modified on 1/13/2016

We know your privacy is important and that is why OnCourse Learning Corporation (“OCL”) is dedicated to making it one of our top priorities. OCL created this Privacy Notice to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and confidentiality. This Privacy Notice is intended for all of [OCL's](https://www.oncourselearning.com/) websites, our mobile site, and our app (the “Site”). Additionally, we may provide external links to third party websites who may have their own privacy notices. We recommend that you read through this Privacy Notice and any other privacy notice if your private information is a concern.

By visiting and using this Site, you agree that your use of our Site, and any dispute over our privacy practices, is governed by this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Service. Because privacy issues change over time, so must our Privacy Notice. We will make sure that we post any significant changes on our Site and update the “Last Updated” date to reflect the date of the changes. If you continue using our Site, it shall constitute acceptance of the updated Privacy Notice

## Our simple privacy notice

We wrote our Privacy Notice in a way that is easy to read and understand. For those of you who wish to read additional technical details of our Privacy Notice, it follows the simple notice.

## Implied consent

By purchasing any of our products or using any of our services, you consent to this Privacy Notice. Additionally, by becoming an OCL customer, you consent to receive tailored content and services, relevant advertising, and other OCL communications.

## What personal information do we collect and why?

Account Information- We may ask for your name, address, email, and phone number. In some instances, our Site may require you to submit your social security number, student federal ID, work history, resumes, professional license information, degree information, education course completion certificates, driver’s license number, company name, company title, and the number of employees at your company. This information is used to administer the creation of your account and to follow state laws regulating your profession. Additionally, we use this information to make your shopping and site experience as a registered user the quickest and easiest possible. When you register with OCL, we may ask for additional information (such as professional interests, career information) to help us offer services, courses, and promotions that may be of interest to you.

_Username and passwords_ – We require usernames and passwords so you are able to securely access your account and purchase our products and services.

_Credit card and banking information_ \- We also collect credit card or banking information so our vendors may process your payment to complete a sale.

_Usage Information_ \- Once you register on our Site, we collect your product and service preferences, purchase history, time spent on our Site, location information, and other account information to better understand user preferences and help us develop better products and services catered to our users. When you take a course, certain information is collected (such as courses selected, tests results, certificates issued, time logged, etc.) which is accessible in your personal profile section.

_Customer Service Logs_ \- When you call or submit a question to customer service, we will need to confirm account information to protect your personal information. Emails and calls will be logged to help us provide you with the best customer service possible.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. These measures involve firewalls, passwords, trained customer service agents, and other industry best practices.

## What do we use your information for?

OCL’s customers are very important to us so we use your information in a number of ways including: improving our user-interface, creating new products and services, tailoring a personalized welcome screen for registered users, measuring user interests and traffic patterns, and informing our customers about products and services that may be of interest to them. We may also share user information with our trusted third party service providers (such as a credit card processing company), OCL’s affiliates, and trusted partners. We’ve also been known to send offers for discounts or free services on our Site!

## Accessing and changing your account information

If you are an OCL registered user, you can update your personal profile by logging in and making changes in your personal profile section. If you have questions about an order, you may check your order status by contacting customer support at [corp@oncourselearning.com](mailto:corp@oncourselearning.com) or call 866-806-9900. If you ever decide to unsubscribe from marketing and/or service email communications, you may contact customer support or by unsubscribing whenever you receive an email from OCL.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance (“CalOPPA”)

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the CalOPPA. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance (“COPPA”)

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA. We do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our Site, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## Changes to our privacy notice

OCL always strives to offer the best possible products and services to our customers; therefore, we will likely have to update this privacy policy from time to time. We will always keep you in the loop by providing a notice on our Site when a material change becomes effective.

## Questions regarding privacy

Still want more information about our Privacy Notice? We would love to hear what you think and feedback is always welcomed. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, our privacy practices, or your dealings with us, you can contact:

OnCourse Legal Department 20225 Water Tower Blvd. Fourth Floor Brookfield, WI 53045

## The additional privacy notice details

## Automated information being collected

We collect and store information through a variety of automatic technologies, such as browser and flash cookies; pixels and web beacons about your use of our Site, including device identifying information such as IP addresses; MAC address or other device-specific alphanumerical ID numbers; the make and model of your device; the wireless provider associated with your device; whether you downloaded the app; the source of the download of the App (for example, whether via a particular advertisement for the App); when the App is launched; how many times a particular page within the Site is visited; which features the users interact with; and your device or computer's connection to the Internet. These things allow us, among other things, to improve the delivery of our web pages to you and to measure traffic on the Site.

## Do we use cookies and what kind do we use?

Yes, like most websites, OCL rely on cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow). Cookies enable the Site or service providers to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our Site visitors. These service providers are permitted to use the information collected on our behalf only to help us conduct and improve our business.

_Session Cookies_ \- These type of cookies exist only for as long as your browser remains open. Once you exit your browser, they go away. We use session cookies to maintain information we need to have in order for you to shop on OCL. For example, the session ID cookie that we ask your browser to hold retains the ID for your shopping cart. Without the session ID cookie, you can't add courses or merchandise to your bag and carry it to checkout.

_Persistent Cookies_ \- In contrast to session cookies, persistent cookies last from visit to visit; they do not go away when you exit your browser. We use persistent cookies to give you a more personalized shopping experience and to help you navigate our store more efficiently. We will use your information to enhance your site experience. However, you can use our site without accepting a persistent cookie.

If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We may provide your information to our affiliates or trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, as long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. If you do not wish certain information to be shared for these purposes, send a letter to the OCL’s Legal Department at 20225 Water Tower Blvd., Fourth Floor, Brookfield, WI 53045.

We also make some content, products, and services available through cooperative relationships with third-party providers, where the brands of our provider partner appear on the Site in connection with such content, products and/or services. We may share with our provider partner any information you provide, or that is collected, in the course of visiting any pages that are made available in cooperation with our provider partner. In some cases, the provider partner may collect information from you directly, in which cases the privacy notice of our provider partner may apply to the provider partner's use of your information. The privacy notice of our provider partners may differ from ours. If you have any questions regarding the privacy notice of one of our provider partners, you should contact the provider partner directly for more information.

## Is my information secure?

OCL is committed to doing its best to maintain the security of information collected on our Site. To try to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Private account and customer information is located on a secured server behind a firewall and is properly encrypted. However, as effective as the reasonable security measures implemented by us may be, no physical or electronic security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our Site's servers or databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the internet.
